Father, Husband, Brother. No Man is Just a Soldier.
We Were Soldiers is a action, history, war film directed by Randall Wallace.
The story of the first major battle of the American phase of the
Vietnam War and the soldiers on both sides that fought it.
Lt. Col. Hal Moore, played by Mel Gibson.
Julie Moore, played by Madeleine Stowe.
Maj. Bruce 'Snake' Crandall, played by Greg Kinnear.
Sgt. Maj. Basil Plumley, played by Sam Elliott.
2nd Lt. Jack Geoghegan, played by Chris Klein.
Barbara Geoghegan, played by Keri Russell.
We Were Soldiers is a 2002 American war film co-produced, written and directed by Randall Wallace and starring Mel Gibson (both of whom previously worked together on
Braveheart), Madeleine Stowe, Greg Kinnear, Sam Elliott, Chris Klein, Keri Russell, Barry Pepper, Ryan Hurst, Marc Blucas, Clark Gregg, and Jon Hamm.
The film is based on the 1992 book We Were Soldiers Once… and Young by
Lieutenant General (Ret.) Hal Moore and reporter Joseph L.
Galloway, dramatizing the Battle of Ia Drang on November 14, 1965.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, vietnam
veteran, hero, army, based on novel or book.
The tone is intense.